go across to the management at IC
Lombard they declared their numbers the
management is now with us Mr gopal Chief
Financial Officer Chief risk officer at
IC Lombard General sir thank you so much
for taking our time for us could you
just first start by helping us
understand what were the key highlights
of the quarter that went by what were
the key hits and misses in the
quarter thanks for the question um so if
you look at for the quarter gone by I
think it was a a satisfying quarter for
us uh particularly in the context of um
in this quarter we actually are able to
get the final IID approval for the uh
Dem merger of baka into IC Lombard and
quite happy to note that um the
effective date for the transaction was
8th of September and um over the last
let's say 9 to 12 months that you have
been planning for this integration to be
in place I think happy to kind of report
that we have been able to successfully
from an operational integration
standpoint we have been able to kind of
get the two entities merged into one and
um in that sense um I think extremely a
satisfying quarter um having said that I
think if you look at it from a financial
standpoint again things have been
looking good for us uh if you look at in
terms of gross premiums we were able to
grow for the half year at about
7% uh clearly across commercial lines uh
Health motor of course at this point of
time we continue to take a cautious
stand but overall I would say a
satisfying quad
good afternoon Mr balach Chand Cher also
joining in the conversation uh can you
tell us about the key trends that you're
actually seeing post the second wave of
the covid-19 also uh how has the
recovery been on a month and- Monon
basis for your
company no that's a very very relevant
question because if you look at uh let's
let's look at quarter one I think
clearly we have seen even as a country
we did experience significant uh
increase in number of covid cases and
that's the reason if you would have seen
our quarter 1 numbers we did see a
significant spike in the number of covid
case intimations pretty much what we saw
in one quarter was as good as what we
saw for the whole of the last year in
fi21 in terms of intimations now clearly
things seems to be behind us when we
look at the quarter two Trends again in
line with what you see at a national
level um just to kind of put some
numbers in perspective uh in quarter one
we had to kind of provide for uh covid
claims to the tune of almost about 602
crores uh this number if you look at it
for a half year now that number stands
revised to about 561 crores on a merge
entity given the fact that I said now BX
also a part of the I Lombard family so
for this particular quarter clearly we
are seeing declining Trend in number of
uh covid intimations and we were
actually able to get a right back to the
tune of almost about 67 crores in
quarter two so the trend line seems to
look uh positive
obviously very difficult to predict what
could happen in the future in terms of a
possible third wave but the sense that
one gets is if you look at some of the
other evolved countries where
vaccination rates have significantly
been higher the extent of uh cases which
goes for hospitalization tends to be on
the decline so overall I would say the
trend line on the covid intimations uh
seems to be looking on a positive note
having said that I think on the non-co
health claims particularly in this two
we did see a elevation in the number of
claims uh it could be possible that some
of the customers had possibly postponed
their treatments to take place in this
particular Quarter Two given the
uncertainty or anxiety that they had in
quarter one uh so that's the trend that
we will watch for as to whether the
significant bump up that we had seen in
non-id health intimations in quarter 2
does that sustain or is it more one of
uh increase in number of customers who
have elected to get thems treated in
this
quarter you have spoken in the past
about how there has been a real shift in
health insurance Trend uh post the covid
can you talk to us about consumer Trends
shaping up over there what is the kind
of traction you're
see that's a great question because um I
think from an IC lomard standpoint I
think we are extremely extremely kind of
delighted with the opportunity that the
health insurance space presents and
that's the reason why if you recollect
uh even in quarter one uh what we had
kind of announced was to in order to tap
into this opportunity of expanded uh uh
opportunity we we had kind of announced
um adding almost about thousand people
to our existing head count and all of
the Thousand will go into Frontline
distribution in order to tap tap into
the health opportunity so clearly from
an expansion standpoint we want to
continue to stay invested in order to
reap the benefits of what the health
insurance space presents so that's one
in so far as distribution is concerned
equally on the product side I think
again from an Isis Lombard standpoint
what we have been kind of doing over the
last several years is clearly if you
look at the market largely it was kind
of offering a product which kind of
reimbursed uh the cost of
hospitalization cover a large part of
the out of pocket spends was in that
sense not necessarily covered through
any form of insurance and clearly we see
trend line picking up in that context
wherein customers increasingly are also
looking to put a lot of Investments on
preventive of preventive healthare as
compared to obviously um getting
themselves treated in the event of an
unfortunate Health ailment so in order
to seize the opportunity on the OPD
Sprint as OPD front as well I think we
have been investing on building our own
app we call it as the IL take care app
which pretty much kind of takes care of
the entire gamut of uh health care needs
more from a preventive standpoint in
terms of in case if you're required to
make uh a visit to a um get do a health
checkup if you want to get your
medicines ordered online we have a tie
up with the pharmacy chain so all in all
I think the I take care have enables a
customer to take care of their entire
gamut of healthcare needs and some of
the pilots that we have done in the past
over the last 12 to 15 months those
Pilots have clearly shown us encouraging
results again happy happy to know note
that the number of downloads that we
have seen on use of the I take care app
as we speak has crossed about 8 lakh
80,000 in number and that's an area
where we are continuing to stay invested
so overall I think we are extremely
excited with the opportunity that the
health insurance segment is presenting
and we are investing both in terms of uh
expansion and distribution and at the
same time the Innovation that we can
bring about in so far as a product
construct is concerned
in H1 actually you would have seen a
rise in claims your combined ratio is at
114% could you tell us more about your
assessment of the claims ratio uh is
this largely D driven by uh the covid
related Health claim and also do you see
uh where do you see it actually
normalizing going
ahead sure I think that's again a great
question so let me just kind of break
down the uh impact of the loss ratios
between the or the combined ratios
between the couple of quarters you are
right I think if you look at quarter one
we kind of reported roughly about 122
23% combined ratios for the company as a
whole and within that if you would have
seen particularly covid claims was as at
its peak on the health side we kind of
reported a loss ratio which was between
168 to 170% uh that's the quarter one
numbers now if you look at uh Quarter
Two uh against the 122 123% that we
reported as a combined ratio for the
company as a whole in Quarter Two that
number stands revised to about 10
15.3% um and within that if you were to
look at the health segment in line with
what I had talked about of the fact that
clearly covid Trends seems to be on the
decline non-id however seems to show
some kind of an increase the loss ratios
for quarter two on the health segment
has come down from 168 170% to about 78%
this of course includes as I said the
right back of about 67 crores that we
were able to uh see in Quarter Two given
the fact that we had conservatively
estimated for loss reserves in q1 um on
a steady state I think what we could
expect is uh I think in so far as the
trend line of non-id health intimations
is something that we will keep a watch
on uh and hence to that extent we could
possibly at least for let's say maybe
the next quarter uh see the loss ratio
the health slide slightly on the higher
side given the fact of the right back
that we had in quarter 2 but at the same
time what we have been affecting is
price revisions particularly on the
corporate Health segment which we are
talked about even as a part of our q1
earnings call which wherein we exhibited
price increases ranging between 15 to
20% and upwards and clearly we are
seeing that trend line continue even in
this quarter and happy to note from an
is Lombard standpoint that even on the
corporate renewals even with the
increased pricing we have been able to
retain more than 9 % of the account when
it came up for renewals but the impact
of the increased pricing on the loss
ratios is something that will play
through over the next three or four
quarters so hence to answer your point
maybe in the immediate foreseeable
quarter you could actually see some kind
of increase in the health loss ratios
numbers but as we move along into the
next let's say three or four quarters
the benefit of increased increased
pricings will start to play through and
we should start seeing Health loss
ratios getting normalized